Guide to the Bronislaw Malinowski Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1869-1939; Series I
  - Correspondence of Bronislaw Malinowski
    - Weigall, Marian H., 1917-1918 (Box 8, Folder 640, Reel 5)
    - Weigall, Myrme [fragment], undated (Box 8, Folder 641, Reel 5)
    - Wells, Peter, 1938 April 8 (Box 8, Folder 642, Reel 5)
    - Westermann, Diedrich H., 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folder 643, Reel 5)
    - Westermarck, Edward A., 1916-1936 (Box 8, Folder 644, Reel 5)
    - Western Union, 1936 November 5 (Box 8, Folder 645, Reel 5)
    - Wheat, Carl I., 1926 May 10 (Box 8, Folder 646, Reel 5)
    - Wheeler, G. C., "T. B.", and Boremius, Anne-Marie, 1912 August 13 (Box 8, Folder 647, Reel 5)
    - White, Leslie A., 1937 November 25 (Box 8, Folder 648, Reel 5)
    - Whitehead, Mrs. G., 1932 June 14 (Box 8, Folder 649, Reel 5)
    - Williams, Henry T., 1935 September 19 (Box 8, Folder 650, Reel 5)
    - Willis, Dorothy, 1936 July 6 (Box 8, Folder 651, Reel 5)
    - Willis, Olive M., 1936 July 27
    - Wilson, Dorothy, n.y. February 18 (Box 8, Folder 652, Reel 5)
    - Wilson, Gerald H., 1937 January 28 (Box 8, Folder 653, Reel 5)
    - Wilson, Godfrey Baldwin, 1935-1938 (Box 8, Folder 654, Reel 5)
    - Wissler, Clark
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1869-1939 Folder 14
    - Witkiewicz, Stanisław I., 1914, 1936-1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 655 - 656, Reel 5)
    - Witowska, Antoniora, 1930 December 22 (Box 8, Folder 657, Reel 5)
    - [Witmer], Helen [Leland], 1936 November 8, 18 (Box 8, Folder 658, Reel 5)
    - Wolska, Stefanja, 1929 March 14 (Box 9, Folder 659, Reel 5)
    - Wood, E. D. K. [fragment], undated (Box 9, Folder 660, Reel 5)
    - Woodson, Carter G., Editor of The Journal of Negro History; letter of introduction to S. W. Green written for Malinowski, 1926 May 27 (Box 9, Folder 661, Reel 5)
    - World Population Conference, Sir Bernard Mallet, Chairman of Advisory Council, 1927 August 23 (Box 9, Folder 662, Reel 5)
    - Gilbert Wright, Ltd.; Montgomery Butchart, 1936-1938 (Box 9, Folder 663, Reel 5)
    - The Yale Review, H. McAfee, 1935 May 29 (Box 9, Folder 664, Reel 5)
    - Yoltan, Anne, 1937-1939 (Box 9, Folder 665, Reel 5)
    - Young, Kimball, 1928 October 10 (Box 9, Folder 666, Reel 5)
    - Y. M. C. A., London Central, 1937 April 28 (Box 9, Folder 667, Reel 5)
    - Zeitschrift für Freie Deutsche Forschung; Johann L. Schmidt, undated (Box 9, Folder 668, Reel 5)
    - Zeitschrift für Rassenkunde, 1935 April 12 (Box 9, Folder 669, Reel 5)
    - Zeleński, Tadeusz, 1938 June 9 (Box 9, Folder 670, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified, A-L, 1907, 1932-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 671, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified, M-Z, 1936-1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 672, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified, A-Z, 1913-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 673, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified, A-Z [in Polish], 1915-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 674, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified [first name only], 1918-1938. undated (Box 9, Folder 675, Reel 5)
    - Unidentified [fragments, no signatures], 1918-1927, undated (Box 9, Folder 676, Reel 5)
    - Letters of introduction written for Malinowski in connection with research in New Guinea, 1914-1915 (Box 9, Folder 677, Reel 6)
    - Invitations and form letters, 1926, 1933, 1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 678, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence re: naturalization of Malinowski as a British subject, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 679, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence re: miscellaneous purchases; includes bills and receipts, 1931-1938 (Box 9, Folder 680, Reel 6)
    - Letters of recommendation and evaluations by Malinowski and others, 1937-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 681, Reel 6)
    - Banking and investment correspondence
      - Bank of New South Wales, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 682, Reel 6)
      - Commercial Bank of Australia, 1915-1916, 1918
      - Spar-und Vorschubkasse für Handel und Gewerbe, 1924 July 21 (Box 9, Folder 683, Reel 6)
      - Kunerolwerke, Emanuel Khuner and Son [business correspondence with Paul Khuner], 1927-1931 (Box 9, Folder 684, Reel 6)
      - Westminster Bank Ltd., 1930-1931, 1936, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 685, Reel 6)
      - Barclay's Bank Ltd., 1938
      - Blankart and Company, Zurich, 1931, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 686, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence regarding real estate
      - House repairs, Oberbozen villa, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 687, Reel 6)
      - House repairs and realtors' estimates, 6 Oppidans Road, London, 1931-1936 (Box 9, Folder 688, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence regarding travel and shipping arrangements
      - New Guinea expedition: bills, receipts, invoices, 1914-1917 (Box 9, Folder 689, Reel 6)
      - New Guinea expedition: Burns, Philp and Company invoices and receipts, 1914-1918 (Box 9, Folder 690, Reel 6)
      - Northern Liners Agency, 1920 August 20 (Box 9, Folder 691, Reel 6)
      - Cunard Steam Ship Company, 1926 January 21
      - Bills and receipts, 1923-1936, undated (Box 9, Folder 692, Reel 6)
      - American Express Company, 1931-1934 (Box 9, Folder 693, Reel 6)
      - William B. Feakins, Inc., lecture and concert management, 1931 November 25 (Box 9, Folder 694, Reel 6)
      - African conference: Imperial Airways Ltd., 1934 (Box 9, Folder 695, Reel 6)
      - African conference: correspondence, memoranda, and clippings, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 696, Reel 6)
    - Passports and travel permits
      See: Series IV. Special Files, 1902-1946 Folder 4
      See: Series IV. Special Files, 1902-1946 Folder 5
    - Legal correspondence
      - Anton Kinsele, lawyer in Bolzano, 1924-1933, undated (Box 10, Folder 697, Reel 6)
      - H. M. Inspector of Taxes, 1926-1938 (Box 10, Folder 698, Reel 6)
      - Currey and Company, W. D. Macpherson, re: guardianship of and covenants for Malinowski's children and income tax, 1931-1938 (Box 10, Folder 699, Reel 6)
      - Currey and Company, W. D. Macpherson, re: codicil to Malinowski's will, and estate of Sir David O. Masson, 1935-1937 (Box 10, Folder 700, Reel 6)
      - Currey and Company, W. D. Macpherson, re: establishment of a hostel next to the Malinowski residence, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 701, Reel 6)
  - Correspondence of Elsie Malinowska
    - Bainbridge, J. P. [copy by E. R. M.], 1914 November 23 (Box 10, Folder 702, Reel 6)
    - Beutelberger, Maria, 1933 May 10
    - Clarke, Edith, 1931 September 24, n. d. (Box 10, Folder 703, Reel 6)
    - Corbett, Catharine, undated
    - Eagle Star and British Dominions Insurance Company, 1920 October 21
    - Gilruth, Mrs. J. A., 1915 December 6 (Box 10, Folder 704, Reel 6)
    - Gulland, John W., 1915 October 19
    - Hancock, William, 1919 February 9
    - Johnston, Monica, undated (Box 10, Folder 705, Reel 6)
    - Khuner, Paul, 1918 February 27
    - Lewis, Aletta, n.y. July 8 (Box 10, Folder 706, Reel 6)
    - Lewmon, John, 1918 March 4, May 7
    - Masson, F[lora?] M., 1912 July 9 (Box 10, Folder 707, Reel 6)
    - Masson, J. I. [incomplete], 1924 April 27
    - Masson, [Mary?], undated
    - Mayo, Dorothea, n.y. January 13, August 11 (Box 10, Folder 708, Reel 6)
    - C. N., 1922, 1924
    - R[udolf], R[osa], 1930 November 20 (Box 10, Folder 709, Reel 6)
    - Sexton, Helen, n.y. February 11
    - W. B. S. [Spencer, W. Baldwin], undated (Box 10, Folder 710, Reel 6)
    - Unidentified correspondence and miscellaneous items related to Elsie Malinowska, 1913-1917, 1933, undated (Box 10, Folder 711, Reel 6)
  - Correspondence of Józefa Malinsowska
    - Correspondence with friends and relatives, 1869, 1909-1917, undated (Box 10, Folder 712, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence with C. G. Seligman about her son, 1914, 1916, undated (Box 10, Folder 713, Reel 6)
    - Correspondence of others [found in Malinowski's papers], 1912-1939 (Box 10, Folder 714, Reel 6)
- Writings, Lectures and Research Materials, 1910-1944; Series II
  Series II has the following subsections: a) lectures and lecture notes; b) interviews and public statements; c) articles, introductions, and reviews; d) books and related manuscripts; e) fieldwork materials; f) notes and fragments.
  "Lectures and lecture notes," "fieldwork materials," and "notes and fragments" are arranged alphabetically by subject, since many of these items are not dated. The remaining subsections are arranged chronologically, with undated material file at the end of each section.
  - Lectures and lecture notes
    - Lecture [fragment] to the Junior Scientific Society of Oxford: anthropology as a science, applied to the subject of war, undated (Box 11, Folder 1, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes [in Polish and English]: class structure and religion, undated (Box 11, Folder 2, Reel 6)
    - Lecture: "Cultural Contact and Morality"
      See: Series II. Writings, Lectures and Research Materials, 1910-1944 Folder 29
    - Lecture notes: culture, undated (Box 11, Folder 3, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes [London lectures and Berkeley lectures and notes]: culture, undated (Box 11, Folder 4, Reel 6)
    - Lecture: "Culture as a Determinant of Behavior," notes, drafts, and final text delivered at Harvasrd Conference of Arts and Sciences, 1936 September 7 (Box 11, Folder 5, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: the family, undated (Box 11, Folder 6, Reel 6)
    - Lecture: "Food Rites," complete text, in commemoration of Jane Harrison and her work, undated (Box 11, Folder 7, Reel 6)
    - Lecture: "The Foundations of Faith and Morals," Riddell Memorial Lecture.
      See: Series II. Writings, Lectures and Research Materials, 1910-1944 Folder 122
    - Lecture: "Life and Lovemaking in Melanesia," in Malinowski's hand, undated (Box 11, Folder 8, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Linguistics; "general linguistic discussion summed up", undated (Box 11, Folder 9, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Linguistics; "the power of words and words of power", undated (Box 11, Folder 10, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Linguistics; "translation of untranslatable; words in life on paper; analysis of homonyms", Circa 1929 (Box 11, Folder 11, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: "The Loss of the Third Dimension," lecture delivered to the Leonardo Society, Balliol College, 1931 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 12, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Magic, undated (Box 11, Folder 13, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Magic; "elements of magic", undated (Box 11, Folder 14, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Primitive Economics
      See: Series II. Writings, Lectures and Research Materials, 1910-1944 Folder 50
    - Lecture [fragments]: Primitive Law; annotated text of Malinowski's conclusions, undated (Box 11, Folder 15, Reel 6)
    - Lecture outline [typed]: Primitive Warfare; for the Tavistock Psychological Clinic, 1937 November 9 (Box 11, Folder 16, Reel 6)
    - Lecture [fragment]: Race; three copies, includes a questionnaire, undated (Box 11, Folder 17, Reel 6)
    - Lecture and synopses of lectures: Race and Education, undated (Box 11, Folder 18, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes and outlines: Race and Education; material for South African addresses, n.y. July (Box 11, Folder 19, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: Religion, undated (Box 11, Folder 20, Reel 6)
    - Lecture Notes: Religion, Magic, and Science, undated (Box 11, Folder 21, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes [one page]: A Sense of Community, undated (Box 11, Folder 22, Reel 6)
    - Lecture and lecture notes: Sex; later incorporated into The Sexual Life of Savages, 1923, undated (Box 11, Folder 23, Reel 6)
    - Lecture: "Sex in Modern Life", n.y. July 24 (Box 11, Folder 24, Reel 6)
    - Lectures of the Trobriands, concerning the method of field work and land tenure
      See: Series II. Writings, Lectures and Research Materials, 1910-1944 Folder 188
    - Lecture notes: War; "conclusions of lecture V", undated (Box 11, Folder 25, Reel 6)
    - Lecture notes: War and Socialism; "war and socialism in Australia," "socialism in Germany before and during the war", undated (Box 11, Folder 26, Reel 6)
  - Interviews and Public Statements
    - Records of Conferences of the British Social Hygiene Council and the Board of Study for the Preparation of Missionaries, kept by Malinowski; notes on speeches by others, notes for a speech by Malinowski, lists of participants, 1928, 1930, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 27, Reel 6)
    - Report of the Conference of the Board of Study for the Preparation of Missionaries and the British Social Hygiene Council, held at High Leigh [includes the text of discussions, memorandum, and conclusions], 1928 October 5-9 (Box 11, Folder 28, Reel 6)
    - Report of the Conference of the Board of Study for the Preparation of Missionaries and the British Social Hygiene Council [includes statements by Malinowski and the text of the discussions], 1930 January 10 (Box 11, Folder 29, Reel 6)
    - "Primitive Science and Religion;" complete text and six drafts of a broadcast talk, criticisms from listeners, 1930 October 26 (Box 12, Folder 30, Reel 6)
    - Summary of dialogue on African education, B. Malinowski and I. Schapera, 1936 January 15 (Box 12, Folder 31, Reel 6)
    - "Personal Opinions" on the comtemporary world situation, notes and three typed drafts with corrections, Harvard Tercentenary, 1936 August 21 (Box 12, Folder 32, Reel 6)
    - Response by Malinowski to a questionnaire [copy included] re: a supreme court of organized learning; issued at the Harvard Tercentenary of Arts and Sciences, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 33, Reel 6)
    - Notes and outlines on the debate between Malinowski and A. Radcliffe-Brown; introductory remarks and arguments on each side, with annotations by Malinowski, 1938 June 17 (Box 12, Folder 34, Reel 6)
    - Interview of Malinowski by Eleanor Kittredge: "Human Evolution-Where Does It Lead Us Now?," typed script [with corrections] of article for Ultra Magazine [expanded version of "An Anthropologist looks at War," New York Times Magazine, Oct. 12 1941], 1941 December 8 (Box 12, Folder 35, Reel 6)
    - Minutes recorded by Malinowski at a meeting at Raymond Firth's; discussion of anthropological method attended by Schapera, Bateson, and others, undated (Box 12, Folder 36, Reel 6)
    - Notes for a radio broadcast on anthropology and human experience, n.y., n.m., "Tuesday, the 8th" (Box 12, Folder 37, Reel 6)
    - Text of a dialogue between Malinowski and K. F. Mather on war, property and the family; Handwritten notes and typed script, undated (Box 12, Folder 38, Reel 6)
  - Articles, Introductions, and Reviews
    - Review of Two Representative Tribes of Queensland by John Matthew in Man, 1910 September (Box 12, Folder 39, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Tribal and Intertribal Relations in Australia, by G. C. Wheeler, in Man, 1911 February (Box 12, Folder 40, Reel 6)
    - Review of Grundlinien einerVergleichung der Religionen und Mythologien der AustronesischenVolker and of Die Mythologie derAustonesischen Volker, by P. W. Schmidt, in Folk-Lore, 1912 March 31 (Box 12, Folder 41, Reel 6)
    - "Tribal Male Associations of the Australian Aborigines," reprinted from the Bulletin de l'Académie des Sciences de Cracovie, 1912 April-June (Box 12, Folder 42, Reel 6)
    - Review of Across Australia, by Baldwin Spencer and F. J. Gillen, in Folk-Lore, 1913 July 1 (Box 12, Folder 43, Reel 6)
    - Review of Les Formes Elémentaire de la Vie Religieuse, By E. Durkheim, in Folk-Lore, 1913 December 31 (Box 12, Folder 44, Reel 6)
    - Review of Rest Days; A Sociological Study, by Hutton Webster, in Man, 1914 March (Box 12, Folder 45, Reel 6)
    - Review of Der Mensch und Seine Kulter, by Neophilosophos Tis, in Man, 1914 May (Box 12, Folder 46, Reel 6)
    - "The Natives of Mailu: Preliminary results of the Robert Mond Research Work in British New Guinea," reprinted from Transactions of the Royal Society of South Australia, vol. xxxix, 1915 (Box 12, Folder 47, Reel 6)
    - Letter to the editor regarding article by Mr. Ormsby-Gore on anthropology and administration, in Nature, 1916 November 24 (Box 12, Folder 48, Reel 6)
    - "Kula; the Circulating Exchange of Valuables in the Archipelagos of Eastern New Guinea," Man, 1920 July (Box 12, Folder 49, Reel 6)
    - "The Primitive Economics of the Trobriand Islanders," galley proof and reprint from The Economic Journal, 1921 March (Box 12, Folder 50, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Group Mind, by William McDougall, in Man, 1921 July (Box 12, Folder 51, Reel 6)
    - "Ethnology and the Study of Society," Economica, 1922 October (Box 12, Folder 52, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Golden Bough: A Study in Magic and Religion, by Sir James George Frazer, in Nature, 1923 May 19 (Box 12, Folder 53, Reel 6)
    - Review of Die Kultur der Gegenwart: ihre Entwicklung and ihre Ziele, by Paul Hinneberg, in Nature, 1923 September 1 (Box 12, Folder 54, Reel 6)
    - "The Problem of Meaning in Primitive Languages," reprinted from The Meaning of Meaning by C. K. Ogden and I. A. Richards [with annotations by Malinowski], 1923 (Box 12, Folder 55, Reel 6)
    - "Psycho-analysis and Anthropology," Psych e, 1924 April (Box 12, Folder 56, Reel 6)
    - Review of Le Monde Social des fourmis, comparé à celui de l'homme, by Auguste Forel, and resultant letters to the editor, in Nature, 1924 July 19, August 23 (Box 13, Folder 57, Reel 6)
    - Review of Leaves from the Golden Bough, by Lady Frazer, proof with corrections, for Nature, 1924 December 13 (Box 13, Folder 58, Reel 6)
    - Mutterrechtliche Familie und Ödipus-Komplex [published in Psyche as "Psycho-analysis and Anthropology"], proof with corrections for Imago, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 59, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Children of the Sun, by W. J. Perry, first draft [for Nature ], 1924 (Box 13, Folder 60, Reel 6)
    - Review of Folk-Lore in the Old Testament: Studies in Comparative Religion, Legend, and Law, by Sir James George Frazer, proof with corrections for Nature, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 61, Reel 6)
    - Review of Die Ursprunge der Lyrik, by Heinz Werner [for Mind ?], Circa 1924 (Box 13, Folder 62, Reel 6)
    - "The Forces of Law and Order in a Primitive Community," reprint of discourse delivered to the Royal Institution of Great Britain, 1925 February 13 (Box 13, Folder 63, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Social and Political Systems of Central Polynesia, by Robert W. Williamson, in The New Statesman, 1925 June 13 (Box 13, Folder 64, Reel 6)
    - Review of six titles in The History of Civilization Series, in, proof and final printed copy Nature, 1925 July 11 (Box 13, Folder 65, Reel 6)
    - Review of Primitive Law by E. Sidney Hartland, in Nature, 1925 August 15 (Box 13, Folder 66, Reel 6)
    - "Forschungen in einer mutterrechtlichen Gemeinschaft," Zeitschrift Für Völker-psychologie Und Soziologie, 1925 September (Box 13, Folder 67, Reel 6)
    - Review of Primitive Labour, by L. H. Dudley Buxton, typescript and reprint [with annotations] from Nature, 1925 December 26 (Box 13, Folder 68, Reel 6)
    - "Magic, Science and Religion," S cience, Religion, and Reality, ed. by J. Needham, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 69, Reel 6)
    - "Magic, Science and Religion,"typed extract for Cambridge Essays on Science and Religion [with corrections], [ca. 1925?] (Box 13, Folder 70, Reel 6)
    - Reviews of The Races of Man and their Distribution, by A. C. Haddon; Pygmies and Bushmen of the Kalahari, by S. S. Dornan; The New Decalogue of Science, by E. A. Wiggam; The Southern Seas: Wanderings of a Naturalist, by Dr. W. Ramsay Smith; and The Central Caribs, by William Curtis Farabee; galley proofs for Nature, [ca. 1925] (Box 13, Folder 71, Reel 6)
    - Review for the The Threshold of the Pacific, by Dr. C. E. Fox, handwritten and typed drafts for The [London?] Times, [ca. 1925] (Box 13, Folder 72, Reel 6)
    - "The Role of Myth in Life" Psyche, 1926 April (Box 13, Folder 73, Reel 6)
    - "The Life of Culture" Psyche, 1926 October (Box 13, Folder 74, Reel 6)
    - "Anthropology," with annotation by the author, entry in The Encyclopedia Britannica, 13th edition, pp. 131-140., 1926 (Box 13, Folder 75, Reel 6)
    - "Psychoanalysis" and "Psychology," notes for drafts of The Encyclopedia Britannica articles for in the author's hand, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 76, Reel 6)
    - "Primitive Law and Order," first draft typed and in the author's hand, and typed copy for the printer [published in Nature, Vol. 117?], [1926?] (Box 13, Folder 77, Reel 6)
    - Review of Australian Totemism, by Geza Roheim, typed draft for the Times Literary Supplement, [ca. 1926?] (Box 13, Folder 78, Reel 6)
    - "Prenuptial Intercourse between the Sexes in the Trobriand Islands, N. W. Melanesia," reprinted from The Psychoanalytic Review [became Chapter III of Sexual Lives of Savages ], 1927 January (Box 14, Folder 79, Reel 6)
    - "Lunar and Seasonal Calendar in the Trobriands," reprinted from the Journal of the Royal Anthropological Institute, Vol. LVII, 1927 January-June (Box 14, Folder 80, Reel 6)
    - Review of Race and History, by Eugene Pittard, in The New Republic, 1927 March 16 (Box 14, Folder 81, Reel 6)
    - Review of Ritual and Belief in Morocco, by Edward Westermarck, galley proof for Nature, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 82, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Mythology of All Races, Vol. IV, Finno-Ugric, Siberian; by Uno Holmberg, in The Saturday Review of Literature, 1928 April 7 (Box 14, Folder 83, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Mothers: a Study of the Origins of Sentiments and Institutions, by Robert Briffault, and The Mystic Rose: a Study of Primitive Marriage and of Primitive Thought in its Bearing on Marriage, by Earnest Crawley, revised by T. Besterman; galley proofs for Nature, 1928 June 28 (Box 14, Folder 84, Reel 6)
    - "The Anthropological Study of Sex," drafts [in the hand of Raymond Firth?] for Berlin Congress, [ca. 1928?] (Box 14, Folder 85, Reel 6)
    - "The Anthropological Study of Sex," Verhandlungen de I. Internationalen Kongresses Für Sexualforschung [Berlin vom 10 bis 16 Oktober 1926], 1928 (Box 14, Folder 86, Reel 6)
    - Review of the Kiwal Papuans of British New Guinea, by Gunnar Landtman, in Folk-Lore, typescript, proof and final copy, 1929 December 18 (Box 14, Folder 87, Reel 6)
    - Review of Are We Civilized? Human Culture in Perspective, by Robert Lowie, in The Listener, typescript, proof, and final copy, 1929 December 18 (Box 14, Folder 88, Reel 6)
    - "Kinship," proof of encyclopedia entry, The Encyclopedia Britannica, 14th edition, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 89, Reel 6)
    - "Marriage," handwritted draft of the article for The Encyclopedia Britannica, with corrections, Circa 1929 (Box 14, Folder 90, Reel 6)
    - "Marriage," reprinted from The Encyclopedia Britannic a, 14th edition, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 91, Reel 6)
    - "Practical Anthropology," printed copy with annotations [ Africa ], 1929 (Box 14, Folder 92, Reel 6)
    - "Kinship," Man, 1930 February (Box 14, Folder 93, Reel 6)
    - Review of The Evolution of Modern Marriage, by F Müller-Lyer, in The Listener, typescript and final copy, 1930 April 2 (Box 14, Folder 94, Reel 6)
    - Review of "Fasti" of Ovid, edited with translation and commentary by Sir James George Frazer, in Nature, typescript, proof and final copy, 1930 June 7 (Box 14, Folder 95, Reel 6)
    - "Race and Labour," The Listener, 1930 July 16 (Box 14, Folder 96, Reel 6)
    - "Race and Labour," notes on Buel; fragments of early typed drafts with corrections, [ca. 1930] (Box 14, Folder 97, Reel 6)
    - The Colour Bar, précis of the article "Race and Labour" in The Listener, with corrections, [ca. 1930] (Box 14, Folder 98, Reel 6)
    - "Science and Religion," The Listener, proof sheets and printed final copy, 1930 October 29 (Box 14, Folder 99, Reel 6)
    - "The Rationalization of Anthropology and Administration," Africa, 1930 October (Box 14, Folder 100, Reel 6)
    - Foreward to The Red Men of Nigeria by James Rhodes Wilson-Haffenden, [1930] (Box 14, Folder 101, Reel 6)
    - Preface to The Primitive Mind and Modern Civilization, by Charles Roberts Aldrich, typed draft and proof, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 102, Reel 6)